Guide to the Charles Herr and Betsy Goldsmith Papers TAM 727
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Charles Herr and Betsy Goldsmith Papers
1914-1998
1969-1998
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Herr, Charles
Goldsmith, Betsy
TAM 727
1 Linear Feet in 1 record carton
Charles Herr, also known as Charles Fernandez Herr, is a clinical psychologist in New York City. Before receiving his Ph.D., Herr worked with Ann Rosenhaft on the publication of the periodical New York Socialist starting in 1973. Betsy Goldsmith was part of the National Staff of the Socialist Party, USA in 1992. The Charles Herr and Betsy Goldsmith Papers contain materials concerning socialist political and social endeavors in the greater New York City area during the late 20th-century. Materials include correspondence related to the publication processes for the New York Socialist and issues of the New York Socialist publication from 1973 to 1977, as well as pamphlets, newspaper clippings, and flyers concerning the Social Democrats, USA and activism against corruption in New York City in the 1970s. Correspondence of Charles Herr focuses on potential articles for the New York Socialist, and letters between Herr and Ann Rosenhaft concentrate on the creation and implementation of the City Crisis Coalition to counter political corruption in New York City.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Betsy Goldsmith in 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.054
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
Charles Herr, also known as Charles Fernandez Herr, is a clinical psychologist in New York City. He received his Ph.D. from Columbia University Teachers College in 1992. Before embarking on his Ph.D., Herr worked with Ann Rosenhaft on the publication of the periodical New York Socialist starting in 1973. Betsy Goldsmith was part of the National Staff of the Socialist Party, U.S.A. in 1992.
Scope and Contents
The Charles Herr and Betsy Goldsmith Papers contain materials concerning socialist political and social endeavors in the greater New York City area during the late 20th-century. Materials include correspondence related to the publication processes for the New York Socialist and issues of the New York Socialist publication from 1973 to 1977, as well as pamphlets, newspaper clippings, and flyers concerning the Social Democrats, USA and activism against corruption in New York City in the 1970s. Correspondence of Charles Herr focuses on potential articles for the New York Socialist, and letters between Herr and Ann Rosenhaft concentrate on the creation and implementation of the City Crisis Coalition to counter political corruption in New York City.
Socialism -- New York (State).; Socialism -- United States -- 20th century.; Socialism and youth -- United States.; Socialism -- United States -- Periodicals.; Socialism.; Corruption investigation -- United States -- Citizen participation.; Political corruption -- New York (State) -- New York.; Social Democrats, U.S.A.; Rosenhaft, Ann.
- Letters to the Press, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- New York Socialist Periodicals, 1973-11-1977-04 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Socialist Newsletters, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Socialist Flyers, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pledge Plan and Dues, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Psychoanalysis Papers, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Coalition on Economic Crisis Conference, 1975-03-01-1975-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Socialist Party Correspondence, 1975-11-11-1977-06-26 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Socialist Reaction to Portugal, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- New York Socialist Pre-Publication, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- National Committee Mailing, 1975-06-1975-08 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- New York Socialist, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
- Young People's Socialist League, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- New York Socialist Periodicals, 1973-11-1977-04 (Box 1, Folder 15-20)
- Socialist Party Newsletters, 1973-04-1976-01 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Socialist Party Statements, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- City Crisis Coalition, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 23 - 24)
- Socialist Party USA, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Socialist Tribune, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Social Democrats, USA, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 27 - 28)
- Newsletter of the Democratic Left, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Newspapers, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 30 - 31)
- Socialist Unity, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Socialist Congressional Campaign Book, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 33)